The first chapter of AI video is going
to be around using new fancy AI
technology to do old media formats. As
in linear video, you watch from A to B,
right? Broadcasting. But of course, once
you get with code, you open up so many
more new possibilities. But eventually,
you create code. You're not entirely
delegating video creation to the AI.
You're assisting. We very much believe
in augmenting humans. Putting the human
at the center of all this just net you
the best content. For starters, you have
code that describes a video. So you have
the sort of PowerPoint structure and
that transforms into video and then you
have other helpers that you know are
more similar to our current world coding
assistance and I guess in that sense
when you're creating things of that
nature the user is co-creating your kids
kids are not going to be reading and
writing they're going to be watching and
listening almost exclusively text is an
amazing technology the world is built on
text but the question is if the friction
to storing information ideas and
knowledge in a video format versus a
text format is as easy as that right
will it mean we will still be reading
and writing
[Music]
Hello everyone. Welcome back to the AI
native dev. Uh today we have uh Victor
Riparbelli with us on it. Victor uh I've
known Victor for maybe about five years
now or uh roughly that and he is the CEO
and co-founder of Cynthsia which is a
super exciting company and the leading
company today uh when it comes to AI
native video. uh and we'll talk a lot
about kind of creation with AI and uh
and and decisions made along the journey
and also a little bit about the journey
itself which is really interesting in
its own right uh and apply you know what
what type of learnings uh can we take
from that to the world of that so Victor
thanks a lot for coming onto the show of
course happy to be here so Victor maybe
just to get us started a little bit tell
us uh a little bit about what Cynthia is
uh and what it does sure so theia is the
the world's largest leading um platform
form for AI video for businesses.
Essentially, what we do is we help our
customers land their messages with the
highest degree of effectiveness, right?
And the highest degree of understanding
of whoever is on the other end of that
message. And in 2025, that's not with
slide decks or text. That is with video.
Today, people want to watch and listen
to their content. Um, everyone is
different. Of course, I'm sure you read
a lot. I also still read a lot. But if
you look at the average consumer, right,
people really want to watch and listen.
That's what they do their free time when
no one is watching. listen to podcasts,
watch Tik Tok videos, YouTube, Netflix
and so on and so forth. But when it
comes to our work life, most of the
content most of us consume is still in
text format and in slide format. And
we've essentially built a platform um
that kind of kind of started with this
avatar technology which really was a way
to replace a camera that you use in the
real world with a sensor. We go around
and you film things with AI so we could
generate the footage if you will um of
people talking specifically. Um but
since then we've now built an entire
platform around us. So we have a video
editor that enable you to actually
finalize the video. You can add in your
you know screen recordings, text
animations, whole bunch of other things
to actually finalize the video. Uh it's
a content management system. It's a
publishing platform with our own
proprietary video player. It essentially
is one platform that helped you go from
an idea all the way to delivering that
video to your end consumer and
understanding uh how that how does this
is is impacting uh them. One of the key
things around our platform, which I'm
sure we'll talk more about today, right,
really is this this aspect of enabling
people who had never made a video before
to make a video, right? And so when you
enter the app today and you begin making
a video, if you've ever made a
PowerPoint in your life before, you
should be able to pick it up in in kind
of 5 minutes. And that means that what
we've essentially done is in some of the
world's largest companies, we've created
thousands of video creators who used to
only be able to create documents and
slides, but now they're they're making
videos. Um, That's kind of like where we
are today that you the next uh 12 24
months. One of the things that's always
been a huge part of our thesis is that
the first sort of chapter of AI video is
going to be around essentially using new
fancy AI technology to do old media
formats as in linear video you watch
from A to B, right? Broadcasting. Um but
of course once you can generate video
with code, you open up so many more new
possibilities. videos can be
interactive. They can be two-way
conversational and they can do a whole
bunch of other things we couldn't do
with normal video, right? And so I think
the next couple of years that's really
what um what's going to define the next
chapter of the year. Yeah. No, super
exciting and we're going to drill a lot
more because like each of these things
is uh is sort of a a whole topic to
unpack. Um maybe so starting so I love
how the sort of the platform has this
ability for someone who hasn't created a
video to create it today. I use it as
the kind of uh really kind of a great
example of uh how you can kind of enter
disrupt uh the business world by really
taking something in the world of AI that
allows you know powerful creation but
requires a lot of change you know a lot
of uh it's a very different it's an
entirely different way of creating video
uh as compared to whatever taking a
camera and uh and starting to shoot it.
Uh so I think that's really uh powerful
but it's also probably like a a
reasonably high friction type uh
environment on it. So maybe first of all
like describe a little bit more like
what is involved when someone does
create a video in Cynthia like what is
that experience just for context and
then maybe let's talk a little bit about
who's like the ideal creator in this
context. Does it even matter if they
have previous video creation skills? I
think there's so many um you know
parallels to to to death uh you know to
cook here. So I think when you make a
video right we tend to think uh a lot
about like the production of the video
right which is like technically how are
kind of each of the frames kind of
created right is it with a camera is it
with AI you sort of technically make the
video um and that part I think you know
we've made super easy right that's
essentially you go in you select an
avatar you type your script you use this
like basic powerpoint editing
functionalities to put something
together and most people who are office
workers I think should be proficient
like figuring out how this works you
know that's not that's not
not that difficult especially if you
compare to like using Adobe Premiere
like some expert tool where most people
would go in and just blank right they
wouldn't know what to do. This is a Is
it fair to sort of think about this as
the story board or the like like it's
the it's this it's the script it's the
narrative like whatever the chapters of
the video that yeah it's it's kind of if
you think of a power like making a slide
deck right like you have different
scenes um you have the scripts which
what your app will say we made a whole
bunch of like design decisions around
not giving you a timeline for example
which are different layers in the video
um because as soon as people see that
they begin to freak out they don't know
what a video is right so we
intentionally kept it almost like
PowerPoint with speaker notes and kind
of relatively simp simplistic UX kind of
I would say from a technical standpoint
most people can create a video right but
the thing is that a video is not just
technical part of it the video is also
storytelling right it's how do we
actually put together what is a good
video right how long is a good video
what should you include in the video
what should you not include in the video
and I think what we found generally
speaking right is that actually that's
actually the thing that people struggle
with the most by now most of us know how
to write a document like we know how to
write an email we know how to text with
people but video is a new format, right?
You can't just like write a PowerPoint
doc and then just copy paste that into
Synthesis and make a video. That's not
going to be a great video. In a video,
you have a visual language that you want
to use to communicate, right? You have
animation, all these other things. Um,
so there's like the technical part of
actually making the video and then
there's kind of more the creative aspect
of like actually putting a good video
together. And that's actually what
people struggle with the more in
Tunesia. So, we built a bunch of of tech
to to to ease this, right? um we've
built we call assisted creation which is
essentially kind of like an agent that
we've taught how to use the editor on
your behalf. So what that could do is
you can give it either you can give it
just a script you've just written kind
of free form or you can also take a URL
it can take a PowerPoint deck it can
take a PDF document basically any
content existing content you have and
it'll take it'll parse it then it'll
turn into a video so it'll write a
script for you it'll delineate into
different scenes it'll also do the
design of those different scenes you
know some of those scenes may have a big
image in it and it'll pull images from
from stock um stock writersh'll use some
of your own assets and other things it
gives you kind an outline. I would say
from where it is today, it's not like a
final video end to end good to go, but
it essentially changes your role as
someone who makes a video from like
coming up with something from scratch to
being an editor, right? The draft is
maybe like 80% there, 85%. You still
want to go around change part of the
design. You want to add something, you
want to remove something. Um, and it's
it's been pretty interesting to see the
progression of uh how many more people
we can kind of bring on to be creators
when you give them a draft to work from
with their content as opposed to asking
them to come up with something from uh
from that's awesome. If I kind of echo
back a little bit of of the pieces here,
you know, the first part is okay, you
kind of you use the sort of the lowest
common denominator or sort of know the
most also I would sort of say maybe the
core piece in which you want the human
to decide or sort of the creator to
decide which is what is it that you want
to say and and I guess the storytelling
piece and the video uh formation or like
how to tell that story and video format
is the part that if you want to
democratize it then you need to help
people uh and so you assist in that but
you have also mentioned like another
aspect it's not like you can imagine
that type of assistance happening as
someone types you know autocomp
completion or a little reviewer or
something like that and I think you even
had you know and have probably still
some of those capabilities um but you're
describing something that is more than
that which is uh just kind of point me
at sources of information and I will
help you form that is that are those
just on boarding exercises of like give
me a PDF and I will create a thing but
now you will engage with something that
is um that is back into that format of
I've got the slides like you just sort
of pre-create the slides but then from
here on you work with the slide or are
these actual kind of degrees of freedom
where you're sort of leaving it to the
LLM say here's a PDF like extract info
from here extract from there and maybe
if you run it again it would extract it
a little bit it is like an entry point
to making a video which a lot of people
use as like the starting point it is
just like an onboarding exercise and you
can you can kind of tune you basically
when you upload your content you can
tune um the agent in in like different
ways, right? You can tell it how long do
you want the video to be, what audience
are you making it for, um and it will
kind of give you first an outline of the
content and then you can actually in
bullet form. So it will give you like a
bulleted formatted list of like what
narrative will be and then from that you
can actually edit the bullet yourself.
So you can add another bullet saying add
in something about blah blah. You can
take a bullet out then after the outline
which is sort of the easiest way for
most people to sort of have an overview
of like what's going to this video. Then
from there it'll expand that into
individual scenes which is an actual
video and then you can of course edit
that out. Right. Right. So it's it's um
it's less iterative than say like a
completely free from like texting where
you just like keep prompting it over and
again just spits out new new versions.
We do ask you to kind of like fine-tune
it a little bit in the beginning to like
what specifically that you're after.
Obviously this is like you know this is
this is like work in progress and I
think I think in in all modalities right
now people trying to figure out like
what is the right degree of automation
for different types of tasks right for
example I think if you're making a Super
Bowl ad which is not our target market
at all there I wouldn't expect
automation to be uh a low degree of
automation right because this is a
really important piece of content like
of those 30 seconds every second uh
really really really matters doesn't you
want that to be absolutely perfect and
that probably means you want to have a
human being very much in charge of like
every single pixel right on the other
hand making like a corporate training
video and your main goal is to
understand help people understand like I
don't some your vacation policy in your
company or something like that right
they want a high degree of automation
because it's a much kind of lower stakes
piece of content um and we operate more
in that category and we operate in the
super category so what we're kind of
figuring out is like what's the right UX
for people to get to that draft but then
also iterate on the draft after Right.
We have a bunch of tools now. So, you
know, once you're in your video, you're
editing it. You can of course use LLMs
to kind of help you extend the scripts
and make it know some more happy, more
sad, like do a whole bunch of things in
there. But we we very much believe in in
augmenting humans as opposed to like
trying to kind of replace like creating
like a fully automatic content
generation machine. I'm not saying that
will never happen. I think we'll that's
definitely the direction the world is
moving in. But we very much believe that
putting the human at the center of all
this just net you the best content,
right? Like there's so I I think we've
seen so many startups both in our space
but also in other spaces the last two
years who try to do completely like end
to end oneshot generation of XYZ and
it's a cool demo but very often right it
just doesn't actually work if you want
to use it in production right if you get
a video that's going to like 70% there
but it's not your brand's colors h it
doesn't really speak about the product
the way you thought it should speak
about then then these things are just
they they kind of remain like very cool
demos
um but don't have a lot of utility,
right? I think that's that's one thing
we've always been like obsessed about is
really working backwards from like
utility, which which sounds very bal and
obvious, but I think in when we have
these hype cycles, right, it could be
easy to to to forget that sometimes.
Yeah. Because it might introduce a bit
more friction to sort of the initial
creation versus just sort of saying a
thing and creating it, which I think I'd
love to draw some analogies to sort of
the world of software development right
now, which you know feels fairly clear
here. So you have uh you know for
starters you have code that describes a
video. So you have the sort of
PowerPoint structure and that transforms
into video and that is in that case the
sort of the the text or whatever sort of
guidance or configuration that you have
about every slide or every one of those
portions uh uh gets compiled if you will
into into into kind of a video format.
Um, and then you have other helpers
that, you know, are more similar to our,
you know, current world coding
assistants in which you can text your
way or autocomplete your way or such
into into creating it. And so that
lowers the barrier because you might
engage with the system with less video
creation uh familiarity or less, you
know, even code familiarity. I think in
that world it's it's a little bit easier
because even after you do all that
process eventually you get words so
everybody can engage you know with that
sort of text that describes what will be
said uh but still you might not have
video familiarity so you have more of
those uh interactive LLM powered like
tap the intelligence that is built into
the system to be able to create the
narrative um and I guess both of those
are like avenues for improvement but
eventually you you create code so you're
not you're not hiding, you know, in uh
or like you're not entirely delegating
video creation to the AI. You're you're
assisting. Yeah, for sure. And and I
think one of the one of one of the
things that was always very important to
us, right, is you could you could
approach video generation as kind of
like a completely end to- end task,
right? Like you put in text and on the
other end you get out pixels basically,
which is how a lot of the like you know
uh like the very generalized video um
generation mod work. Like if you look at
like BO3 for example or runway PK that
that approach has certainly has like a
lot of of of great things about it. Um,
but we always knew that for our
customers and for our workflows, right?
We needed to have an intermediate layer
of editability, right? So, for example,
in in in kind of our videos, our videos
are composed of the avatar models,
right, which produces pixels and footage
essentially like you would get it off a
camera. And then you have all the other
elements of the video which would be,
you know, you have like a lower third
like I'm like I'm having right here,
right? That's the piece of text on
screen. There's some animations. there's
um a transition to the next scene which
winds out everything and fades in or
like there's all these things that makes
a video a video, right? Um and we were
always of the opinion that we need to
actually build that as like
representations we can we can control,
right? So that you can just simply move
a shape around the screen, you can
change the text, whatever. If you had to
prompt that into the video, right, that
that clearly just doesn't work. And so
what we did was we said, "Okay, we have
the footage and we have the editor." And
we invested a lot in the editor. That's
a really uh you know that's a pretty
hard piece of software to build well
because the craft really matters of like
how what it's like to use an editor
right if you think about how do you
represent how do you sort of convey uh
all of these uh uh all of these
designers and is like you know building
Figma pitch like all these kind of
creative tools right that's that's
that's actually you know it's very hard
being building a great product there but
you need that because if you have that
everything is fully editable right and
that's great because then you can start
to help people again like you can prompt
something and it's if they can edit
everything after the fact then it's
great, right? We've seen some products
like you know there's like uh slide deck
generators and video generators that are
that try to do everything end to end and
when things aren't editable um and you
just have to keep reprompting and
reprompting and reprompting. It works
for some use cases, you know, like if
you're if you're if you if you're using
some of these general video models to
clip clips for a music video or B-roll
footage for an ad or something like
that, then it's probably okay, right?
cuz you're not trying you're just like
you just need a 10-second clip or
something and what you want there is
like a lot of creativity in the model.
The ability to just like you know throw
in 40 different prompts, get 40
different outputs and just pick the one
that you like. But for the use case that
we're targeting, it's very different,
right? Like here people don't want to
prompt five times to get a video that
actually works, right? Because it's like
a volume game. People are creating lots
of videos and be able to edit everything
out of the fact. And so when we think
about automation, the important thing
about automation was always that the
automation whatever the whatever the the
the agent spits out, right, is something
you as a user can sit down can correct
yourself and edit and also gives us a
great signal in terms of like what's the
agent good at and what's the agent less
good at, right? So that kind of data
that we start to collect there is
actually pretty interesting. It's almost
like RHF data um in in in some some way.
Yeah. In what people edit. So I love
that and I guess that implies a certain
level of determinism uh between you know
taking taking that those instructions. I
don't want to say that text cuz it's
more than text, but that representation
of the video that you have in every
every scene, every slide uh in the deck
and creating it. I guess how do you
think about um uh kind of I don't know
the room for creativity or or like the
degrees of freedom that you want to
leave uh the uh the LLM. I I'm I'm
certain that you know if you take the
same description that you've sort of
written today uh and you you you
generate or something that you've
created a year ago and you've generated
a video from it that video is not going
to be the same one that probably gets
generated if you kind of run the same
thing today a year later uh just by
virtue of the sort of the the system
getting better right the platform uh
improving I guess how do you how do you
envision today and tomorrow this kind of
determinism versus
um um kind of freedom to uh to evolve uh
on the MLM side. Yeah. So there there's
like two components of this. There's one
the first one is like the actual you
know video models that think of those as
like generating the footage right that
would come off camera and then the other
part of it is kind of like the video
editing which again is like all the the
lower thirds the shapes the animations
the transitions all the stuff that fire
these are like today they're the two
kind of distinct things with two
different models right the first one
replaces the camera essentially gives
you a footage of someone talking to the
camera and the other one take that
footage and edits it into something that
is uh a coherent video into it right the
first one of avatars. And the thing
that's that's unique about uh and I
think the way we look at like the AI
video model market, there's there's a
bunch of different ways you can approach
AI video. And of course, it is again
super use case dependent, right? So if
you really try and and cook it, really
try and like distill it down. I think
the the two main and most important
dimensions of AI video models are
creativity and controllability. So
creativity is a bit as we said before,
right? How creative can the model get?
And creative models are super fun,
right? It's like when you use Delhi,
Sarab or free, whatever. You can type in
literally anything in the model and
something will come up, right? You can
have dogs skateboarding on the beach.
You can have an elephant walking around
Bloom. You can have all these amazing
things, right? And that's super
important. If you're creating creative
content, storytelling content, meme
content, viral content, whatever, then
you really that creative dimension is
incredibly important, right? On the
other hand, you have controllability.
Controllability is um in our case for
example, does the avatar look exactly
the same every time you make a video,
right? But does it change slightly
depending on the brand? Like maybe
sometimes, you know, you'll have a
beard, maybe sometimes you won't have a
beard. Um does it say exactly what you
put in the script? Can you even actually
decide the person
says how fast is it to run? Um you know,
there's all these things that that that
are essentially around like controlling
out. How deterministic is it? Does it
work every single time? Are we in the
kind of slot machine world of of using
big video models where you just put
something, you hope something gets out?
And here there's a very clear
distinction of like what people are
focusing on. We're very clearly focused
on controllability, reliability, costs,
ease of use. Uh right, our avatars need
to look exactly the same every single
time. They need to say exactly what we
put in the script box and all this
stuff. And then there's other models
that started this creativity. Of course,
we are moving towards more creativity in
our models. the new flagship models
we're releasing soon, they'll have, you
know, you'll be able to like prompt
yourself into new environments, prompt
your avatars. We're getting like we're
taking some of that magic, but it's all
kind of built around this idea of like
controllable models because that's what
our users need, right? On the other
hand, you have other models who built
around the creativity and sort of idea,
right? This is where you get more the
your creative directors like um
agencies, etc., right? who who don't
mind like prompting something 50 times
to get to the right scene because if you
have to prompt something 50 times, it's
still I mean 100,000 times more
affordable than actually going on
shooting 50 scenes or even shooting one
scene. Yeah. Shooting an elephant on the
moon in a studio somewhere, right? Yeah.
But of course, everyone wants to have
controllable models that also very
creative. So I think what we'll see is
that eventually probably most of all AI
video will converge on like a model at
some point and the the different
products will will be will be you know
kind of rooted in the same models but
the the the use cases will will kind of
determine um what the products look like
and the UX will be the thing that
differentiates different products right
on the LLM side of like actually taking
that footage and then putting it into
videos um that is essentially a task of
like generating um uh creating a model
right that understands like our editor
that can move shapes around write text
etc. The main vector of improvement here
is just like can we teach a model to go
from more today it's more kind of
templatized right so the way it works is
sort of like you you write the scripts
of course like LLMs to do that and then
based on the scripts we try to figure
out like okay what kind of design which
is basically like a whole bunch of
what's the sentiment do you sound angry
do you sound sort of laughing this is
more like around like should there be
should there be like a process diagram
or should it be like a big picture or
something like that right and then the
model will figure out like okay from
this scene I think it makes the most
sense to have like three bullet points
or I think it makes the most sense to
have like a big image here or process
diagram something like that um and that
works pretty well actually you know like
cuz ultimately when you're making like
simple videos that can be it's a bit
like think of how like you have like 150
PowerPoint templates and the model sort
of picks which one works the best for
your go to market slide which one works
the best for your product vision slide
and so on right and it fills those in
with your brand colors your fonts a
whole bunch of other things that makes
it look real. The thing we're working on
now, right, is though, how do you go the
way you you kind of go above that is you
actually teach a model the language of
video, right? How could you do that?
Well, you could have a model that
watches a lot of video and tries to
figure out, you know, not just like what
kind of template should I pick in, but
like what should this video actually
look like? What does great editing look
like, right? Well, that's something with
like, you know, you'll zoom a little,
you're talking, the camera kind of
slightly zooms in and animation pops up
on the screen. This is much harder of
course but obviously this this is going
to be possible right like I'm sure if
you sat down a model down and watched
like a lot a lot a lot of videos and we
have a whole whole bank of videos
ourselves that make for us right can we
learn to instead of just using kind of a
templated approach to like taking you
from that you know idea to a video to
actually just learning what does your
brand look like what does your font look
like what is the language of video like
for example if you look at modern video
people cut every 8 seconds right it's
like this very like ADHD way of like
making videos, but people like so the
model will probably learn to
automatically cut that, you know, do a
side angle, do a straight on angle, do
like for cool animations. This is like,
you know, definitely more in the in the
kind of like research phase at the
moment. But if you imagine that you at
some point, right, you will have models
that can spit out content and footage
that looks as good as Hollywood films
and is as controllable, you can maintain
dead end, you can do really whatever you
want it to do and you have a model that
understands the language of video,
right? that you can combine the footage
you can generate with the kind of video
ed like with the world's best video
editor that can take that and turn it
into something. And I think that's
that's the path for um that that's the
two main vectors of of of kind of how
you you get to kind of Steven Spielberg
as one AI product of creating. I I I
love a lot of these uh a lot of this
sort of analogy and I think actually it
it it I might be sort of uh you know a
little bit when all you have is a hammer
you know you sort of everything looks
like a nail but I think of it a lot as
being specentric like you are defining
to a level of specification uh what is
it that is in the video and I think what
you've built in synthesia is you've
built a mechanism that allows a fairly
substantial level of control probably as
compared to code still low level of
control right you still don't say hey uh
increase or sort of raise the corner of
the mouth by sort of uh whatever you
know 2 cmters you know at this point
you're still you're you're actually
still allowing a decent amount of
interpretability
uh to the uh to to the model because
it's just kind of unfeasible to describe
the video at that level of granularity.
So as compared to code is probably still
already has some built-in degrees of
freedom but still you you control it uh
uh substantially. But then the other
side of that is adaptability because I
think you talk about creativity and
that's great but but and and I agree
with that but that in turn enables
adaptability. So that you know if you
were to generate a video 10 years ago or
for whatever like 40 year olds like me
you know and and you might uh go easy on
the ADHD and sort of you know allow a
moment for set of scenes to change while
if you're sort of doing it for a
teenager uh you might be much more sort
of snappy in modification. So the same
video can be generated in a way that is
adaptable to to that context right and I
think a lot about that in in the context
of code because you know code has its
own stacks like sometimes it's financial
needs sometimes it comes back again to
sort of user needs and sort of
preference and do people want to you
know get a a clean page or reach page do
they want it corporate looking or do
they want it modern looking uh and and
even in the functionality right do you
want to optimize for latency do you want
to optimize for costs do you want to uh
you know use a specific specific stacks.
All of those are different contexts,
right? And you will adapt uh the code to
that. But you need that spec that allows
you to control that sort of slider
between predictability and adaptability.
Uh and and I think you're using the
better words for the world of video,
which is uh controllability and uh and
uh creativity. Um but is that am I on
track here in terms of describing it's
essentially all the kind of knobs you
can tune, right? and and different knobs
will will work different like different
people, different users will have will
have different needs. Um, as I said, I
do think all these things eventually
will convert, but it's kind of a matter
of like what's your wedge into the
market and and and how do you how do you
position yourself? Um, the exciting
thing as to your point here, right, is
of course that, and I kind of also said
that a bit in the intro, I think, is um
I think we're right at the brink of I
think right now like video and AI video
look very similar, right? It's it's
basically like how it was produced.
That's that's different. But that's
going to change pretty dramatically,
right? Um as to your point, right? What
we're going to be able to do when every
video is generated with code and there's
no sensors involved. Everything is
literally just like zeros and ones. Then
we can start to make an entire new type
of video experience where like maybe um
you don't like the ADHD experience of
like Tik Tok cutting like eight sec
every 8 seconds. That that should really
annoy you if you had to watch a video
that's built like that. Mhm. You could
just not watch it like that. You'll get
a version of the video that is maybe a
bit, you know, more kind of slow paced.
It's not as like Tik Ty, but then maybe
like, you know, your daughter or someone
else who's like younger than you prefers
to watch that style of information. They
and they can do that, right? There's a
lot of parallels. What you usually use
is like, you know, when the first
websites kind of were conceived uh back
in the day, they kind of looked like
newspapers on screens to some extent
because that was kind of like what we
imagined back then, right? was like the
most obvious thing to do because
everyone knows what a newspaper is. It's
a page with some information and let's
just replicate that on our screens. And
of course that was a great product and I
think that's kind of like where we are
right now in AI video. But then
eventually like we figured out well
actually kind of a website and newspaper
are two very different things right a
newspaper like you print it every single
morning you send it out to 10 million
people all read exactly the same thing.
Um on a website you can update the
information in real time right you can
have a feed that's personalized to
whoever is actually watching it. you can
drive interactivity between users but
one click you can access a gazillion
pages on the internet um and all the
things that makes a website very
different than a newspaper right so I
think what will happen is we'll like
these mediums will diverge and I think
what we think about as AI video right
now right will eventually be that right
it'll be more about a system that has
been instructed by someone like me for
example a user to communicate a message
and then the system can kind of figure
out how itself like well maybe guy wants
to deliver this way Victor wants to
deliver this Okay, that's built across
linkers, body languages, what avatar do
you want to use, etc. But that's very
clearly the way all all of the stuff is
going to go, right? And and that's
always actually been the thing that
excites me the most. I think in our
space there's going to be two main
directions going to be one direction
which is going to be the Hollywood film
uh entertainment thing. There's like so
much to do there still of just like
enabling some great Yeah. just to sort
of replicate to the current status quo
or like you know produce the thing that
can be done uh today with sort of
physical uh means or digital but uh but
production means but in a much much
cheaper and sort of uh iterative way but
eventually producing the same type of
like output. Exactly. It's kind of like
when people you know use a computer to
write a book, right? You write the book
and you publish it. And of course that's
like I mean way easier than sitting with
like a typewriter back in the day or at
at some point carving it in you know
stone or something like it's it's much
much easier and much much faster and has
a huge kind of value added to it. But if
you're someone with a with with a
message, right, a lot of like young
people say that they'll start a blog or
there'll be a blog and and Twitter,
right? That's like constantly evolving
and it's not really like the format of a
book. It's something very different. And
I think it's like it is all the all
these trends that we see with every time
we invent new media technologies, this
exact same thing happens. And that's
about to happen for for AI video as
well. And that's definitely direction
we're more excited about. I think
there'll be other companies who'll be
focused on like, you know,
entertainment, fictional content, like
video as we kind of know video today.
And what we're the most passionate about
is like how do we evolve video into
something new, right? I think that's
that's that's just both on a personal
level, I think it's very very exciting
and fun to do and but I also think from
a from kind of a business opportunity
perspective um there's just so much so
much knowledge to be driven here if you
take training and education which is
something that's you know very close to
our use cases today.
um when you can watch a video and you
can ask the video a question or the
video can quiz you or examinate you on
the content you've just consumed. Um
change the content uh depending on what
you're interested in, right? You may
have a kid learning mathematics and this
particular kid loves football, right? So
let's make all the examples that makes
everything that you're learning about
math is about football. That makes when
if I'm learning math, it would be about
music because that's the thing that that
I'm the most passion about. If it's you,
it's something else, right? Just the the
the the societal value we can create
with these kind of like personalized
learning. It's essentially like everyone
will have kind of a personalized tutor
in some way, right? That's so exciting.
And there's I guess other examples, you
know, in in in the corporate world, in
the business world where where amount of
value this will create is just going to
be it's going to be immense. Uh I I love
uh I love that both kind of you know the
sort of the mission aspect of it. uh but
also uh the technology and the kind of
lens on creation and I guess in that
sense when you're creating things of
that nature you the user is co-creating
uh with uh with a platform and you end
up having sort of these three-way uh
creation uh whatever combo here right in
which there's the original creator that
scaffolded the system and defined you
know these things have to be there and
they are um they're set in stone there's
no there's no degrees of freedom over
here like it would always be these brand
colors it will always be you know these
are the topics that need to be examined
on etc. Um then you have the the AI
platform itself uh or the sort of the
platform in this context uh filling in
the gaps and sort of uh uh uh
implementing simplifying creation and
bringing it and then you have the user
kind of with whatever their input is
maybe it is whatever the favorite uh
step that interacts with the platform.
So, it's a it's a new type of creation,
not just delivery, but you need to
enable the delivery of that, otherwise
you're you're hindered. Sure. Yeah.
Super excited. I've got like a million
more sort of uh topics to sort of ask
about uh about the creation side. Maybe
we'll come back to that, but I want to
uh switch a little bit to talk about the
the journey of Cynthia because it's just
super interesting. So, you started the
company back in 2017
uh uh kind of the AI winter type period.
at the time it wasn't uh it wasn't like
the best fundraising strategy uh to come
uh and come up with a you know today
you're this sort of you know sort of
high-f flyier you know I think you
announced that you're over 100 million
uh in ARR and you grew there like
massively fast and uh and that's
incredible uh but it didn't look like
that in the early years of it can you
tell us a little bit about just a bit of
an abbreviated story of the uh of the
early years uh yeah for Sure, for sure.
Um, yeah, I think in many ways I think
we're a kind of a a classical story of,
you know, looking looking like fools for
three or four years. Um, but then, you
know, eventually turned out that that
the kind of bet we made back in 2017, we
found the company was uh was was right.
But the very story is that I'm from co
making Denmark like grew up there. Um,
did a bunch of things by myself, worked
in the daily startup ecosystem. uh you
knew that I wanted to build a company,
knew I didn't want to build like
accounting tools um and and kind of
business process things. I love science
fiction. You say you haven't. You've
sort of built something a bit more
creative than that. Yeah.
Uh yeah. And and back then I was like
building like HR tools, stuff and it was
like I learned a lot from it, right? I
was just like on a personal level I love
sci-fi. I love Frontier Tech and I
wanted to do something that so I moved
to London and I spent a year trying to
figure out like what I wanted to build.
This was just when AR and VR were kind
of like in in in kind of a hype cycle.
The Oculus had just came out and
everybody thought that by now we would
definitely all be in VR headsets all the
time. Um I I I love VR still to this
day, but I I kind of back then felt it's
it's not really there yet. Like there's
this just like there's like too many
obstacles. It's out of my control to
build a big company around it. And but I
met Professor Matis Ner co-founder today
who um had also looked at VR but he kind
of looked at more of the content
creation angle. And he done this this
paper called face tof face which really
was the first time the world saw a
neural network producing photorealistic
video frames automatically. Um and this
paper like made quite a lot of quite a
big big stir and and and I saw it as
well and I just got obsessed with it.
you know, I felt like this is super
early and of course it, you know, it
barely worked and we look back today, it
it doesn't look very impressive, but I
just felt like something very magical
here, right? I this is going to change
first how we create content, then it's
going to change content itself as we've
just discussed. And I just felt there
was so many parallels, you know, like uh
I love music. Music is my big passion
when I'm when I'm not working and
especially electronic music. Uh and I
saw so many parallels to how we, you
know, like by now like a couple of years
ago, we started to digitize how you make
music, right? You can sample things
you're having to use real estate. You
can build synthesizers. You can create
sounds yourself out of nothing, right?
And everything got brought to us in
terms of like new music genres,
democratization of access to music
production and so on. And it felt like,
you know, what's what's happening now is
just that we're digitizing um video,
right? And there's so many analogies to
all the creative music tools that we're
using. So I got very obsessed with that
idea. Right. Yeah. By the way, that uh I
didn't clue into that analogy. That
makes a lot of sense, which you've gone
from whatever a physical guitar to being
able to reproduce that sound on uh on
the computer as an analogy to you could
produce a thing with a camera. Uh and
you know, now you can generate that on
on screen. So, good job. Just like I
love that analogy. Yeah. I think there's
actually so much of like um my
experience like tinkering around these
tools uh in my in my in my childhood
that really you know it's one of the
things it's like in your back of your
head you're not like consciously think
about all the time but understanding how
you make content digitally I think it
was definitely helpful anyway um we felt
like you know let's start trying to
start a company around this uh it took
me a very long time to convince Matias
because at this point in time I was 25
years old I had no I had absolutely zero
qualification to start this company at
all but I was just obsessed with the
idea Yep. And we managed to get a get
kind of a team together and we're trying
to raise some money. Totally impossible.
Got turned down by like 80 100 investors
something like that. Everybody just
thought uh you know the idea was kind of
crazy which it was like it it was you
have to extrapate a lot to to see this
actually panning out. But also at that
point in time especially in London here
like everybody wanted to fund like PhDs
right who would go out and they would
hire like the best free PhD friends and
they would like go on some journey to
create some big AI company. And some of
those companies, I think our strength
actually end up becoming the fact that
I'm not a PhD and that I'm a person,
someone who thinks commercially, but
people definitely didn't like that. At
some point, um, my my co-founder
Stephan, he sends an email to Mark Cuban
cold before we found this email in a in
a leaked Sony hack. Um, and he sent a
very short email just saying, "Hey,
we're building this thing. We think
you'd fit very well. You know, he
understands technology, understand
media, would be." He replies within 3
minutes. Very interested. Sends a bunch
of questions. We email with him for 10
hours non-stop. never get on call with
him. Um, and he ends up investing a
million dollars with which which was the
founder of the company. And the lesson
there was that Mark had himself
implemented the face toface paper at
home with a tutor. He we did not have to
convince him at all that in 10 years
time you can make a Hollywood film with
your laptop. He completely bought into
that. He was essentially just evaluating
the team, right? Um and um and I think
that was like if you're doing something
crazy, you want to try and find someone
who shares like your crazy vision of the
future because it's with VCs, right?
It's so hard to convince them something
they don't they don't already believe if
it's not like uh if it's if it's not
like part of the current dogma of like
the tech community. Yeah. And the the VC
world is very much you only need to find
one, but sometimes you need to talk to
so many. I mean, exactly. the the Mark
Cuban email is like it's like a part of
startup lore now you know sort of like
sort of I've heard that story now being
told not by you you know of people just
sort of in part is like they'll hold on
sort of faith on it uh and part sort of
the craze of it but I guess what what I
don't know is like how many such emails
like the ones it's not that you sort of
picked hey there one person we're going
to email is Mark Cuban
I
mean definitely hundreds maybe even a
thousand right we're just desperately
trying to find someone to um kind of
help you get going on the journey.
And and I think you know looking back
like it's I understood why it was a
difficult pitch like I had no I was 25
years old had no qualifications start
the company at all at least on paper. Um
it was a crazy idea. It wasn't clear
what the real use case if the technology
was even going to work. Um but I'm very
grateful that you know that Mark took
the bet on us. Um, and as it always is,
right, like raising money is like a is
is is a milestone, but the real hard
part began like after we got the money
and we're like, "Okay, great. So, no one
believes in us. We have a million
dollars. What can we realistically like
build and sell?" And this is what year
is this? Like 2017, you started the
company. When are we now? This is 17.
So, we we kind of we kind of in spirit
the idea originated in 16. We raised the
first money uh in in October 2017.
Um, and I think kind of like what we
what we essentially did when we found
the contrast, we did what you're
supposed to not do, which we bet on a
technology, not on a specific use case,
uh, or product, right? Um, and so we had
to kind of figure out, okay, what can we
build backwards from? So we ended up in
this idea of like AI dubbing, which is
like you give us a real video, not a
generated video, we'll translate it to a
different language for you. Um, but
we'll not just replace the voice over,
we'll also reanimate the face so it
looks like you're actually speaking in
like Spanish, Italian, whatever. And I
think the issue we had there was like,
you know, makes a lot of sense. It's
like you're an advertiser and if you
live in Europe where you've definitely
seen like really bad dubbed ads, right,
where like the mouth's completely out of
sync in the German versions. If you can
kind of know for 10K or whatever can fix
that for you and all your ads look like
they were shot natively in whatever
language that you're put in, that makes
sense. If you're Netflix and you invest
a lot of money creating content, then
you could take all those films, you can
make them look like they're actually
shot natively in German or French. that
should have some kind of like economical
um there's been economic abuse there,
right? I I love how this is a a European
pain point or a painoint felt more in
Europe on it. We had Mati on the from 11
Labs on the uh on the podcast as well
and they also a bunch of years later
started uh in that pain. But I think it
was just a you feel it more closely when
you live in a in a non-s single language
uh ecosystem compared to the very
interesting because like the first the
first two funny rounds were were very
very very difficult. um not just because
of this but it was definitely also a
thing that like the American VC
ecosystem didn't understand the pain
right they kind of like you could
explain to the yeah I kind of guess that
makes sense but you haven't actually
felt it firsthand or like you know if
you're a company and you're kind of
trying to penetrate many different
markets uh it's actually really hard
right and it's big value proposition of
the platform today like it is for for 11
labs but but essentially that was the
thesis we we built this thing this is
back when you know this is like GANs
were were like the thing back then the
technology basically It did work if you
look straight at the camera without
looking away. And we had two PhDs
sitting for like two weeks to create a
30-cond clip. So, it was more kind of
like a visual effects. We were all kind
like a visual effects um you know studio
with a proprietary technology. Um and
after having done it for a few years, we
did we did a million dollars in revenue
or something like that. Um which is
which is not terrible at our stage,
right? It kept us alive. But it was very
clear to us that first of all, what
we're building was a painkiller. Sorry,
it was a vitamin, not a painkiller. Um,
people thought it was like cool, but no
one would like scream and yell if we
disappeared the day after, right? We
were not in control of the go to market
because we were selling this to video
professionals like agencies, production
companies, Hollywood studios, and we
were such a small part of like we did
this very famous David Beckham ad,
right? And of obviously you know 98% of
the bulk of the work of of making that
ad was like someone comes up with idea
that David Beckham should do this ad
someone pitch it David Beckham someone
arranges it and films it and then we
were like the very small part at the end
where we were translated to different
languages right so we were not in
control of our go to market at all like
we're basically at the whim of like all
these agencies deciding to work with us
um but more importantly also just didn't
scale like the economics just didn't
make any sense and so we kind of went
back to the drawing board we just went
out and and spoke to hundreds maybe even
thousands of people to try and
understand like what is video, you know,
why do people make video? Um who's not
making video but wants to make video.
And I think that was one the advantage
we have being like very young and being
very naive is that you can really
approach a space with zero baggage,
right? Um and what we discovered was
there all these people in the corporate
world and like smaller companies and
they're contacting us because they they
think our technology does something it
doesn't actually do, but they really are
very intrigued by it, right? And we can
tell these people like they're all
telling us they want to make video but
they can't today. They don't have a
camera. They don't have a user camera.
They can't get budget from their boss.
And they're all saying roughly the same
thing. Saying like I'm making all this
text content and this slide deck content
and I know that no one reads it. And if
they do they forget everything
immediately after. I want to make
videos. I've tried to make videos and it
works much better but the the
scalability of video production is just
not there. It's it's it's so much of a
pain to make videos. You can't edit them
after. And so we we we we spoke to these
people and we figured out pretty quickly
that these these people are not trying
to make Stephen Spielberg films, right?
They're generally making very simple
video like corporate video of like
someone talking to the camera
interspersed with like a screen
recording of someone showing how to do
something picture of a product. It's
very simple concept, right? And of
course for us it was like well that's
actually pretty good, right? Because
there's two things that are uh that are
interesting here. First is the the
domain of video they want us to generate
is much much smaller. It's basically a
person talking to the camera, right? And
secondly, the quality threshold is much
much lower for these people. If you go
to a Hollywood director or some video
agency, right, they will not use your AI
tooling unless it looks exactly as good
as the real thing because, right, well,
that's the bar, right? For these people,
the bar is not real video. The bar is a
PowerPoint. So, they're valuing the
outputs like very differently. And and
that was the thing that we kind of
latched on to. We thought those were
interesting. And that got us to this
idea of avatars, right? Like you create
this sort of digital persona of yourself
or you take one of our off-the-shelf
avatars, you just type in the script and
you magically get a video out. And then
you know we we launched that that
started working really well. There
clearly we hit something there. We built
the editor around it so that you could
finalize the videos yourself inside this
sort of PowerPoint type of UX build
collaboration platform or content
management system and publishing and how
we are today. So yeah, it took us three
or four years of like pain to really get
to think that worked. But um it was also
one of those I think it's a classical
story of like you'd rather be too early
than too late, right? Like we we managed
to survive as long as it's alive.
When when the wave sort of hit us, we
were just so well positioned, right? And
we're years ahead of of any of our
competitors. Amazing story from a
journey perspective. also I think super
instructional for for the world of sort
of software development today because I
think when you look at you know agentic
creation today with software development
and you look at the revolutions I think
that distinction about who is it for is
is so critical you you get such
extremely uh sort of conflicting
opinions from people about sort of
coding assistance and about the vibe
coding and those creations uh and I
think what people often times overlook
is there's a a key distinction between
someone says hey I could have written
this code you know in fact I'm very good
at it uh and this is just about sort of
optimization so does it produce code
that really thinks about all the
different small details that I think
about uh and I'm amazing and that's a
very very high bar clearly something
you'd want very attended um but also you
kind of start doubting you know is it
really producing value here or am I just
you know babysitting more time than I if
I had written it and then you got people
on the other side who are using you know
whatever it is bolt or is 44 or uh or or
lovable uh and you know they before they
couldn't produce software they couldn't
create software just like you know the
user base you're talking about which is
they just couldn't create a video so now
you make it available so like anything
that is functional is is already magic
uh is already something that was not
available it still needs to be good
enough to be something that they will
embrace um and I guess those worlds
eventually converge
uh or they don't really converge. They
they became they become a gradients of
the same uh domain because I guess we
all sort of anticipate that eventually
AI part creation will will permeate the
stack and you know all the way up to the
quality but there will still be
different tools that you would need at
different kind of a quality caliber and
skill set orientation. Sure. I think I
think there's like
the in about like is this like high
stakes content or low stakes content
right? I think it's exactly the same in
in in the code dev world
where what I think is going to happen
right is that we're going to see a lot
of this like low
stakes like very personalized things
like I make the to-do list app. I feel
like everyone always have like they
think they have like the perfect recipe
for a to-do list app, right? And there's
nothing out there that really suits
exactly what you want. That's probably
one of the things for like vip coding it
for someone like me who's not like a I
can sort of duct tape things together
that that might be really cool for me,
right? and and maybe I'll also even pay
like I don't know $5 $10 a month to just
like run this somewhere without any kind
of pains. But that's very different than
me saying, "Hey, let's like vibe code um
a CRM system for synthesis, right?" Like
that is such a high stakes environment
where the quality of the soft really
matters, the security really matters. So
it also feels like it'll just be as to
your point and and what we talked about
before, right? Mine is like Hollywood
films or like uh you know corporate
person just like creating product
marketing content and in your world it's
like are you vi coding a to-do list app
for yourself or something like small
fund for your family or maybe like an
individual tool for your team that does
them like data transformation or are you
like building like a CRM system and it
feels to me at least a lot of the
conversation the last two years people
kind of conflate the two or they think
of it as one right and I think it's just
it's not one like it's it's it's two
like very different use case of course
there are many others And the only thing
is like where we where we've seen a lot
of the the new AI tools work well is
actually delivering value is in these
kind of more like low stakes
environments where you enable people who
haven't been able to do it before to do
something new. Um but in in the kind of
high stakes no matter if you're building
like enterprise CRM software or if
you're making like Hollywood films it's
the the tools are just like not there
yet right but but they obviously will be
at some point. I think maybe indeed we
sort of use this moment to to talk a
little bit about the people uh involved
in in creation here. Um and so I asked
you before you know whether you know
video skill sets uh or video editing
skill sets of today are relevant and as
I understood it they're sort of like
they're helpful in the kind of crafting
of the visual storytelling. So look,
they're they're a little bit available,
but you're mostly sort of making video
accessible to people that are that are
not uh not requiring that skill. I guess
how do you you know, maybe two questions
in one, you know, one is like the
response when you do engage with people
that are maybe stretching kind of your
tools capabilities that do come from
some like they're in charge of videos
and the system. They they do have some
video editing uh capabilities even if
they're not the producers. um you know h
how is kind of their response to it and
then maybe we we kind of go from there a
little bit to say like how do you see
this playing out? Do you do you do you
still see a place for a role for kind of
expert video creators uh or or is this
really meant to be like quite
substantially offloaded uh from uh from
from the world of you know of jobs? All
right. So, what we definitely see is
that people with video experience are
much much better at creating Cynthia.
They become power users much faster and
they have a suite of tools they use
depending on what they're doing, right?
So, obviously, I mean, they're not
trying to create Super Bowl ads inside
Cynthia, but they really appreciate the
tool for ease of use and for the speed
at which they can kind of like churn out
content, right? Um, I think what sets
them apart
is there's like some degree of technical
ability like understanding how a video
works and like you know how should you
place things etc. But really I actually
think it's a lot about something as
esoteric as like taste, right? It's like
how do you make a video that catches
your attention the first 10 seconds,
right? That's not that's not a science.
That's that's kind of like an art,
right? Um what avatar would you pick for
this market? Like well how do you write
a script that's like fun and engaging?
How do we make sure the video is not
like way too long or like way too short?
All this is like taste and that's stuff
that that's taste that you build because
you spend a lot of time thinking about
videos and making videos. And I don't
think uh the more videos you make, of
course, you you'll get better at it also
with the easier. But it's very clear to
me that the people who understand the
language of video storytelling part are
much better at making videos. And I
actually don't think that will go away.
I think that'll remain true for for like
a very long time. the other end of the
scale with like these kind of like new
users. That's something that they had to
learn, right? So, we helped them with
tooling. We talk about this AI agent we
have that can kind of you know make
content on behalf of you and we've come
up with our kind of own framework that
we call
foc some some good ground rules for like
doing that. Um, but I'm very much of the
opinion that I think uh people with with
video skills, right? Of course, you
know, assuming that they kind of migrate
onto this new tool stack, no matter if
it's easier, if it's like more creative,
so they don't resist it. It's too much.
Yeah, exactly. They will be they would
be the best at doing this stuff. They
would have to learn new skills such as
like what does it mean when a video is
not just like broadcasting? How do you
personalize a video meaningfully to
different people? Just like slot filling
with like saying, "Hey guy, hey Victor,
love Cesia, um, you know, love Tesla,
etc." like that's not going to cut it.
How what can you do that's creative and
using LLM and agents to kind of um
create these experience, right? Because
there's so many open-ended questions
there. I think video editors will be
will much better at at doing that at
like kind of evolving into that. For the
casual users, it's uh it's more journey
of like getting up to speed with this
and in designing the app. I love this
design principle called the Maya which
is most advanced yet applicable which
essentially that you kind of have this
sort of window right of like the things
that are like too scary for people to do
and then there's things people like very
familiar with and you want to like
figure out where can you where can you
sit in on this kind of spectrum right
where you can in our case this is said
many times now we're kind of anchored on
PowerPoint users essentially so like
okay make it 75% like PowerPoint because
that makes people feel familiar but then
we also push the boundaries of what you
can do right like there's some new
functionalities you have to learn and
then slowly as more and more people on
board more people try something this
will be moved that window right so I
think in in probably in in like five
years time or something like that maybe
maybe less probably the app will look
very different than does today it won't
be as as anchored on on PowerPoint but
we've taken the user base from something
that we're familiar with to push it into
something that's new and exciting and
and it it almost for the people who've
been with us for a long time feel so
seamless that you don't really think
about it it's like all of a sudden now
you're just making conversational videos
that are interactive that are
personalized by default
um and so on and so forth. So both such
uses are really really really important.
I think I love the May principle as well
and I think probably the best uh uh kind
of example of that is the gestures on
the on the smartphones right where
initially it's like what's the gesture
and at some point there were some some
big changes where you can actually start
being demanding there and and people
want some form of like you know funky
way you would twist three fingers to
sort of achieve some specific examples
and that might be okay. Um I think so so
with that evolution I guess do do you
still see uh kind of I guess this
remaining the notion of like video
creation it sounds like you still see
that as a craft uh and it's just a
different craft than than it is today.
What about the the the production? I
guess sort of the whatever the person
with a camera sort of shooting uh
shooting a video. Do you see that mostly
disappearing? Take a longer timeline,
right? 10 years out. I I do think that's
that's probably like uh a more at risk
for sure.
Um but I I I would still say that
something like video, I mean I came to
video having never done video before,
right? So I learned everything from kind
of starting company. I think it is one
of those disciplines that when you get
into the weeds of it, most people don't
understand like how much work it
actually takes to create like a even a
good looking corporate video of someone
just talks to the camera. When you watch
the video back on LinkedIn, it looks
like oh whatever someone put up their
smartphone and hit play and something in
reality like there's how does the light
fall in right? How does the camera move?
What should the angle be? What should
the framing be?
um like there's all these kind of like
stylistic decisions that you make and of
course those are not usually made by
camera operators but there are like
degree of like also choices a camera
operator has still say I think a lot of
these people are like you know have a
much better foundation for being the
ones who pick up these AI tools and then
become the experts but I think it will
require a migration of their skill set
and I definitely think
that the job of like uh carrying a
camera and filming things in the real
world that will probably be a less
attractive uh business to be in in in
five or 10 years time, right? Just like
being a typewriter um is also not very
um a very true business to be in today.
It's always very hard to I think you
know predict exactly what's going to
happen. And I actually don't think that
like real video is going to die and all
of a sudden everything is going to be
generated. I think we'll put a lot of
value on real video in in in in some
sense just like we still like to see
people playing piano or guitar or um if
we listen to vinyl like there's there's
an emotional part of it and there's also
something I think we just as humans we
we we ascribe some some value to that
right we also still read physical books
despite the fact you could read
everything on a on an ebook so I think
it's going to go away I think it's going
to coexist but um probably what is is
going to be more at risk is a lot of
like the business content you know where
that that's sort of per definition
there's less romanticism, nostalgia,
creativity around it. Um, so I think it
is a market that that will shrink, but I
don't think it's going to like disappear
completely. Yeah. You know, I love that
sort of super succinct on it and I uh um
I love how you keep coming back to kind
of I guess historical references of
music here as a great analogy of you
know what what has happened there and I
do that for a bit and I think clearly we
kind of face that question in the world
of software development of what will
happen to to software developers and I
think it's hard to predict the
specificity but like software
development as a craft hard to sort of
see that going away or becoming any less
important. uh coding as a skill as a
sort of the means of doing it probably
changes uh or or diminishes and maybe
becomes a bit more the you know artisal
carpentry versus the factory line uh
production uh example. I think also one
thing we we see that we did an analysis
recently of how people prompt like our
AI agent to help them make videos,
right? And I don't think it's a surprise
and I'm I'm curious what you're seeing,
but I'm pretty sure it's probably the
same in software development, right?
which is just um maybe an expression of
like this idea of like taste. It's just
like how good people are at prompting
these things, right? Like if you take
someone who's never made a video before
and you ask them to like prompt a video,
describe what you want in the video,
they're clueless time, right? Like make
me a video about our vacation policy.
It's like if you get someone who knows
video and who's an expert on video,
right? You get this beautiful pros. they
clearly have a vision in their mind like
what they want and what they think the
video should look like and so they can
help guide the system to actually create
that for them right and I think that's
the thing that's that's pretty hard to
automate right like we still can't go
into brains and like uh you know kind of
hijack internal LLM to like come up with
the the best idea for like how they
should put something out in the real
world and if you give a very limited
prompt like that is that is what the
system has to work with most I mean you
can add a lot of context around it right
but I think that that's definitely
something that's pretty interesting
right like you you see is in in kind of
people's ability to prompt
um that the more taste they have, the
more experts they are, the much better
at like prompting these systems. I have
a lot of friends that are artists and
illustrators and like when I go in and
try and use mid journey for example, I
face the same problem like I don't know
what to write like I want like a picture
in a jungle. When I have my friends
illustrator do this, right, it's like a
it's like a free paragraph thing and
that's the images he generates is like
10 times cooler than whatever I can do.
Yeah. Yeah. as well as their assessment
of what gets created and I think that's
a really good spot and I think in the
world of software that translates to
kind of architectural and product skills
uh probably more so they're still kind
of elevated I guess kind of a at a
higher resolution that you know use this
library or write that line of code uh
much more about you know the priorities
and the bigger picture. Um, so just
Victor before I uh again so many more
questions so if I sort of to ask but I
think we're running out of time maybe
just to uh uh move out of all of these
and really talk a bit more society.
you've had a an interesting uh uh sort
of statement in a TED talk recently
where you kind of made this bold claim
where you think maybe even as a society
as video creation becomes easier uh text
will play a smaller and smaller role in
our in our world and switch to video
guess what's your what's your prediction
around the societal change that this
type of sort of video generation will
will yeah so I had this uh very
provocative oneliner right which is that
your kids kids are not going to be
reading and writing. They're going to be
watching and listening almost
exclusively, which definitely like set
people off and it definitely gets people
going. Yeah, gets people going. Was also
intention, right? But I think the core
idea just is is is pretty simple. If you
look at the history of media technology,
right? It's very clear that we're always
on this, you know, kind of trajectory
towards more visual content and more
interactive content, which essentially
is content or like information
consumption feels more like the real
world, you know. um that has there's
been a huge barrier to that historically
speaking in the fact that like making a
video for example is way more work in
cost and you know time etc and skill
than it is to like write a document. So
most of the things we've kind of been
consuming has just been text. Text is an
amazing technology. Um text is sort of
like a compression um algorithm in some
sense, right? Like we have something
that happens within the real world and
we can kind of like put that down and we
can store that in a scalable way. And of
course, you know, the world is built on
text. We wouldn't have been there
without without text. But the question
is if the friction to storing
information, ideas or knowledge in a
video format versus a text format, if it
literally is as easy as that, right?
What would that mean for text? Will it
mean we will still be reading and
writing or will it mean that we'll just
default consume almost everything is as
as visual or kind of like real life
content right it's it's a freaky idea
but if you imagine that if you if you
believe that AR and VR in 50 years or
100 years the form fact will be so that
we're just wearing a length something
and we have screens at all times I don't
think it's a completely preposterous
claim to say that we probably will be
consuming most of information
um as as as video and audio and and in
interactive formats. A lot of people
have um very strong feelings about that
and and I I kind of get that, right? I
think we we we we kind of really value
reading in society like sitting down
with a book is like is it probably
represents a lot more than the reading.
It represents the the focused uh area
the
the specific attempt at learning or sort
of you know immersing in a story. But I
think we have to ask ourselves the
question, right, of like if you're
learning something. Um, I think few
people would say, "Oh, we think it's
better to sit down and like read a book
than you're in a classroom with the
world's best tutor who can talk to you
and interact with you and also has a
whiteboard where they can show you
relevant pictures or images or graphs or
flow diagrams, whatever they think
you're learning, right? Like most people
would probably agree that that's a
better way of learning. Um, and that's
probably going to be possible in the not
too distant future, right? Um, and so I
think it'll be interest to see how all
this stuff pans out, right? And of
course I'm being a bit tongue and cheek
when I say that. I think it'll probably
still be a use for text like texting,
etc. But I do think a majority of the
way we consume information is going to
move to being video driven. Um, and I
kind of ended on this. I think the
thought that I have a lot, which is it's
it's so interesting how we put like so
much more value on reading books,
including myself, right? I I read less
than I did five years ago for sure
because I've just found that often I'll
buy a book on Amazon and it's 200 pages
and I'll spend like a day reading it and
feeling half the time reading it feeling
like I'm they're just rehashing the same
examples over and over with so much
filler in a lot of these book which
makes sense because there's you can't
you can't you can't publish a book
that's 50 pages long, right? Yeah.
Exactly. You can't sell it for sort of
any real amount. Yeah. You'd feel
cheated. Yeah. Exactly. And so often
I've just found like when I want to
learn something new, right? I go on
YouTube and I watch a 25minute video,
but I feel almost guilty for not reading
the book and watching the YouTube
videos. Um, and that's so that's that's
that's something like I think philosophy
is kind of interesting like why clearly
like if it's again if it's music or
something, right? Obviously much better
to learn that in a YouTube video we can
hear something and see someone playing
as opposed to like sitting and like
reading sheet music or reading a book.
It's just it makes no sense to try and
read music from a book, right? And I
think a lot of cases like that. Um, and
then maybe the last uh thought I had on
this was I think there's this uh there's
always this sort of moral panic about
like new technologies that's been
consistent throughout all world history.
And one of the things we're hearing a
lot right now is that young people they
can't focus. Their attention spans are
decreasing. Uh they just need like you
know quick dopamine hits from like Tik
Tok videos. Um, and you know, maybe
that's right, but I have this progative
idea like what if young people are just
becoming so good at consuming
information because they they consume at
such high velocity all the time that
they're actually just really bored by a
200page book. You can't we can't keep
our attention because why would you, you
know, you can watch a YouTube video
that's super dense, super interesting,
it's exciting, it's communicated
extremely well, and then now you're
forced to sit and read this like 200page
book which is is is not very exciting,
right? So the question is like are we
getting better at consuming information?
and that's kind of reflected in the
content that we consume or becoming
lazier and our ADHD brains are just like
taken over and we can't focus in
anything. I don't have the answer, but I
feel like that that's an angle that's
very rarely discussed, right? Like
everyone always goes to kind of like the
the negative impact of saying like
people can only watch like 30 second Tik
Tok videos and I just I just I thought
that was kind of an interesting idea to
to try around with. First of all, like I
love that you're sort of uh challenging
the conversation. I think like as long
as uh as long as you're sort of doing it
to sort of facilitate a conversation
versus of you know I don't think there's
any like agenda in sort of you know
sharing this it's more about sort of the
the narrative and I you know I initially
was dismissive when I sort of saw this
like oh Victor's just being uh just sort
of you know stirring uh stirring some
mess here. Uh but that I did think about
emojis you know are actually like a good
example probably of a live uh a live
example of something that that literally
is happening. people are switching to a
visual uh and and I even like an old
person like me sort of still sort
of appreciates sort of the value of
conveying an emotion in that fashion
versus a bunch of words. Um and I guess
the the part that I uh am still kind of
uncomfortable with is is almost thinking
about the degrees of freedom that we
leave ourselves. Uh and so I think the
difference between watching a video or
having someone illustrate to you versus
reading a book is that it leaves room
for imagination. Right? when you read a
book then then you actually get a lot
less you get it takes more time and but
to an extent you get a lot less
information because there's only so much
that can be described uh in the book
especially when you're talking about uh
uh uh maybe in business books it's a
little bit different but like in a
storytelling type setting and so it
leaves you the degrees of freedom uh you
know that but we're talking about living
to the LLM uh and I guess the question
also is like how do we how do we balance
those on it but but I agree with you
that society will move towards
kind of the path of least resistance uh
and you know what is uh what is of a
means of sort of running and and scale
um so it's interesting to sort of see
how how things play out. I totally and I
think the argument around um your
imagination right is the one that I met
with the most often and I think that's
very true for sure. Um yours in a video
you're generally like served everything
and there's less you have to do less
imagining. Um but on the other hand,
right like a lot of that book could be
consumed as like a podcast for example
or like audio get that imagination and
and that that's an example many people
listening to this are doing precisely
that and you know I'm a big audio book
fan and so yeah and and I mean I don't
have kids right but but if I did I'm
also pretty sure I wouldn't be like hey
you know just just stay on TikTok you
know just ditch the
books it's not that I'm kind of like you
know that I'm we will look back at this
period in time and this evolution is
very different as as we are right now
because we always do, right? Like my
favorite example of this is if you go
back to like the 40s um when when radios
kind of became mainstream, something
everyone had, right? The parents you you
could find all these like old newspaper
clips, right? Where parents are outraged
that their kids are like sitting in
their rooms and they're listening to
these like cheap lowquality radio
novels, right? They never leave their
room, they don't want to go out, they
just want to sit in their room and
listen to these novels, which is exactly
what people say about like Tik Tok
videos or computer games, whatever
today. And you know just in in my
childhood I I grew up uh obviously
spending a ton of time on my computer
and playing lots of computer games. I
remember like this when I was uh I guess
was like around 10 11 12 13 years old
something like that right and there was
a very real fear that you become a
school shooter if you play too much
Counter Strike right or that you become
like a violent person. Um there's
famously a Senate hearing around Mortal
Kombat, right? Like 2D Mortal Kombat,
which um people were outraged because
they were convinced that, you know, this
would create a generation of young
violent men that had learned to fight
from like playing too much 2D Mortal
Kombat. And it's like we look back at
this stuff today, right? It just is
absolutely like ridiculous. There's a
kernel of truth to some of it for sure.
But I think we'll I think we I'm very
curious to see like in in 30 40 50 years
time when I'm going to be sitting
scrolling TikTok in the retirement home
and I'm going to be like I was right.
Yeah. At a time in which we were cool
but yeah exactly. We'll see if that
survives. Uh Victor this has been
excellent. Thanks a lot for uh coming on
the show. Congrats on sort of the
amazing journey and looking forward to
sort of seeing it continue both uh
society uh wise and sort of as the
business evolves. Thanks. Thanks for
coming
on and thanks everybody for tuning in
and I hope you join us for the next one.
[Music]